<record><leader>15127cam a2200397 i 4500</leader><controlfield tag="001">9918140870502836</controlfield><controlfield tag="005">20170317125041.0</controlfield><controlfield tag="006">m     o  d        </controlfield><controlfield tag="007">cr|mn |||a||a|</controlfield><controlfield tag="008">151116s2015    nz      o     100 0 eng  </controlfield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040"><subfield code="a">NZNB</subfield><subfield code="b">eng</subfield><subfield code="e">rda</subfield><subfield code="c">NZNB</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="042"><subfield code="a">nznb</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="043"><subfield code="a">u-nz---</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="245"><subfield code="a">Moving farm systems to improved nutrient attenuation /</subfield><subfield code="c">L.D. Currie and L.L Burkitt.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="1" tag="264"><subfield code="a">[Palmerston North] :</subfield><subfield code="b">Fertilizer and Lime Research Centre, Massey University,</subfield><subfield code="c">2015.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300"><subfield code="a">1 online resource</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336"><subfield code="a">text</subfield><subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="337"><subfield code="a">computer</subfield><subfield code="2">rdamedia</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="338"><subfield code="a">online resource</subfield><subfield code="2">rdacarrier</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="347"><subfield code="3">National Library of New Zealand archived copy</subfield><subfield code="a">text file</subfield><subfield code="b">PDF</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="490"><subfield code="a">Occasional report ;</subfield><subfield code="v">28</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="500"><subfield code="a">Archived by the National Library of New Zealand in PDF (xii, 99 pages).</subfield><subfield code="5">Nz</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="500"><subfield code="a">Hypertext links contained in the archived instances of this title are non-functional.</subfield><subfield code="5">Nz</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="500"><subfield code="a">"This document contains the programme and abstracts of all presentations to the 28th Annual FLRC Workshop at Massey University on the 10th, 11th and 12th February 2015."</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505"><subfield code="a">From source to impact: measuring the nutrient cascade response to EU policies in irish agricultural catchments / Phil Jordan, P Mellander, C Buckley, M Shore, N McDonald and G Shortle -- Focus = farm plans + outcomes + catchment priorities + users / Lucy McKergow, T Faulkner, A Stewart, R Parkes, S Ihaka, S Elliott, A MacKay, M Freeman and B Longhurst -- The matrix of good management: towards an understanding of farm systems, good management practice, and nutrient losses in Canterbury / Roger Williams, H Brown, I Brown, R Ford, L Lilburne, I Pinxterhuis, M Robson, V Snow, K Taylor and T von Pein -- Farming with limits Northland style &#8211; the possibilities when science and community join forces / Helen Moodie, T Stephens and A Brocksopp -- The context and practice of nutrient mitigation on Rotorua dairy farms / Simon Park, T Kingi, S Morrell, L Matheson and S Ledgard -- Can the RMA toolbox provide effective tools to manage the impacts of farming on fresh water quality? / Selva Selvarajah -- Accelerating the adoption of good environmental practice on dairy farms in the upper Waikato catchment / Adrian Brocksopp, M Bramley, N McHaffie, D Burger and M Scarsbrook  -- The farming for the future research project &#8211; understanding the outcomes of lower nutrient input on sheep/beef farms using dicalcic phosphate / Jayson Benge, D Lucock, J Manhire and A Topp -- Soil health assessment of taro farms in Samoa / Danilo Guinto, S Lauga, L Dauara, E Walasi and D Autufuga -- Policy implementation - an update from Horizons Regional Council (introduction) / Jon Roygard -- Environmental farm plans &#8211; our experience in the Mangatainoka catchment / Jess Hughes, J Roygard, P Taylor, D Ryan, M Chakraborty, M Clark and L Brown -- Manawatu accord and clean-up fund project - progress report / Lucy Ferguson, J Roygard, A Deverall, A Cooper, M Clark and L Brown  -- Lake Horowhenua accord and clean-up fund - progress report / Jon Roygard, L Brown, M Clark, L Ferguson, A Deverall and A Cooper -- Adapting Manawatu dairy farms to regional council catchment targets / Terry Parminter and S Ridsdale -- Policy development and implementation - an update from Waikato Regional Council / Alan Campbell -- Policy implementation - an update from Environment Canterbury / Leo Fietje -- Process and outcomes of the nitrogen allocation reference group (NARG) for south Canterbury coastal streams (SCCS) area / Ned Norton, I Lyttle, N Newman, C Hurst and I Whitehouse -- Snakes and ladders: helping farmers implement the nutrient management provisions of the ECAN land and water regional plan / Ants Roberts -- Dairy farming at Ealing, South Canterbury / Mark and Devon Slee -- Certification of nutrient management advisers &#8211; one year on / Philip Mladenov, L Hargraves and J Clayton -- Overseer governance - 2014 and beyond / Caroline Read  -- New irrigation module in Overseer 6.2 &#8211; what to expect / David Wheeler and J Bright -- MitagatorTM: a farm-scale tool to estimate and mitigate the loss of nutrients and contaminants from land to water / Rich McDowell, G M Lucci, G Peyroux, H Yoswara, N Cox, M Brown, D Wheeler, N Watkins, C Smith, R Monaghan, R Muirhead, J Risk and A Old -- MitagatorTM - in action solutions for managing nitrogen, phosphorus, sediment and e. coli loss / Jim Risk, A B Old, G R Peyroux, M Brown, H Yoswara, D M Wheeler G M Lucci and R W McDowell -- Are we on course for a train wreck with soil information and data for sustainable nutrient management? / Andrew Manderson and A Palmer -- A comparison of apsim and overseer predictions of N leaching from a well-drained soil under dairying / Ronaldo Vibart, I Vogeler, R Cichota and D J Horne -- The influence of phosphorus fertility and liming on the forms and fractions of phosphorus leached from organic soils / Bernard Simmonds, R McDowell and L Condron -- Can low water solubility phosphorus fertilisers decrease phosphorus losses from an organic soil? / Bernard Simmonds, R McDowell and L Condron  -- Soil type and moisture affects phosphorus loss pathways, forms and amounts / Bernard Simmonds, R McDowell and L Condron  -- Rootzone reality- a network of fluxmeters measuring nutrient losses under cropping rotations / Diana Mathers -- Soil nitrogen and soil water dynamics in arable crop rotations: estimation with the multiple crop single purpose model / Edith Khaembah, H Brown, J Sharp and R Zyskowski -- Preliminary evaluation of three methods for detecting urine patches in the field / Mike Dodd, A Manderson, P Budding, S Dowling, S Ganesh and C Hunt -- Nitrogen concentration in pasture as a tool for guiding fertiliser requirements / Iris Vogeler and R Cichota  -- On-farm drainage remediation projects to protect Wairarapa Moana / John-Paul Praat, J Sukias and T Faulkner -- Changes in soil carbon stocks of New Zealand&#8217;s grazed pasture in response to variations in management and environmental factors / Miko U F Kirschbaum, S Rutledge, P L Mudge, N Puche, L A Schipper and D I Campbell -- On-farm practices for mitigating N losses to water &#8211; impacts on dairy farm systems in the southern South Island / Dawn Dalley, I Pinxterhuis, R Kyte, R Monaghan, M Hunter and J Kerslake -- Progress with operating a duration controlled dairy grazing system for productivity gain and footprint reduction / Mike Hedley, D J Horne, J A Hanly, C L Christensen, J Howes, M Bretherton and J Margerison  -- An analysis of recent urine patch nitrogen research / Diana Selbie, D Wheeler and M Shepherd -- Soil total N content influences pasture fertiliser n response / Mark Shepherd, A Ghani and J Morton -- Does size matter? the effect of urine patch size on pasture n uptake / Mark Shepherd and S Balvert -- How evenly are N and P loads from animal excreta distributed across the farm landscape? / Innocent Rugoho, C Gourley and S Aarons -- Nitrogen fertilizer management with zone characterization in grazed pasture systems / Jessica Roberts, M Trotter, S Woodward and A Werner -- Management zone delineation in arable crop systems / Dinanjana Ekanayake, J Roberts, A Royal and A Werner -- Understanding and enhancing nutrient attenuation capacity in new zealand agricultural catchments / Ranvir Singh, L L Burkitt, D J Horne and M J Hedley -- An assessment of the denitrification potential in shallow groundwaters of the Manawatu River catchment / Aldrin Rivas, R Singh, D J Horne, J Roygard, A Matthews, M Hedley -- Nitrogen attenuation factor: can it tell a story about the journey of nutrients in different subsurface environments? / Ahmed Elwan, R Singh, D J Horne, J Roygard and B Clothier -- Multi-pronged approach to elucidate nitrate attenuation in shallow groundwater / Roland Stenger, J Clague, S Woodward U Morgenstern and T Clough -- Monitoring stream sediment, nitrogen and phosphorus concentrations in grazed hill country in the Manawatu region / Lucy Burkitt, Mike Bretherton and Ranvir Singh -- Realising the value of remnant farm wetlands as attenuation assets / Chris Tanner, J Sukias and D Burger -- The role of current and future groundwater research in collaborative management of water quality / Hugh Canard -- Southland gravel pits conversion to wetlands: a win-win for farmers and the environment / James Sukias, K Robertson, W Tuckey and C Tanner -- Water quality impacts of crash grazing a hill country wetland / Cameron Black, L Burkitt and R Singh -- Assessment of potential biofilter materials to mitigate methane emissions / Rashad Syed, S Saggar, K Tate and B H A Rehm -- Nitrous oxide emissions during maize cropping / Stuart Lindsey, J Luo, J Wyatt and S Ledgard -- Identifying improvements required to simulate NH3 volatilisation following urine or urea application using NZ-DNDC / Donna Giltrap, J Rodriguez, P Berben, T Palmada and S Saggar -- Routes of DCD uptake in pasture plants: a preliminary glasshouse study / Pranoy Pal, A M S McMillan and S Saggar -- Lab assessment of nitrogen mineralisation from farm dairy effluent, slurry and manures / Moira Dexter, A Ghani, P Johnstone, D Houlbrooke, M Norris, J Sharp and B Longhurst -- Improving the efficiency of fertiliser urea on pasture with ONEsystem&#174; / Bert Quin, A Gillingham, S Spilsbury D Baird and M Gray -- The economic impact of water quality regulation in New Zealand / Graeme Doole -- N limits &#8211; part 1: an ongoing case study of a Canterbury dairy farm / Ron Pellow -- Less cows, more profit, better environment  / Trevor Sulzberger, T Phillips, N Shadbolt, B Ridler and R McCallum -- Impact of on-farm </subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505"><subfield code="a">built infrastructure investments on the provision of ecosystem services: irrigation for dairy systems / Estelle Dominati and A Mackay -- Big storms can cost farmers big dollars / Ian McIvor -- Your soil is valuable &#8211; plant trees to keep it! -- Ian McIvor -- Measuring the comparative cost of environmental compliance and mitigation options for Waikato dairy farm systems / Thomas Macdonald, J S Rowarth and F G Scrimgeour -- Spatial variability of nitrogen supply assessed using soil and plant bioassays / Weiwen Qiu, P Johnstone, D Wallace, N Arnold, B Searle, J Sharp, M Beare and D Curtin -- High rate land passage structures for attenuation at high risk land application periods / Hamish Lowe and S Cass  -- The effects of climate change on nitrogen and sulphur load in percolation water from agriculture landscape / Frank Eulenstein, U Schindler, L Mu&#776;ller, M Willms, A K Sheudzhen, S L Schlindwein, M Tauschke, A Behrendt and M A Lana -- Nitrogen fertiliser use efficiency on west coast humps and hollows / Steve Thomas, A Horrocks and C Tregurtha -- Nitrogen leaching from cut-and-carry lucerne / Malcolm McLeod -- Soil quality monitoring across land uses in four regions: implications for reducing nutrient losses and for national reporting / John Drewry, F Curran-Cournane, M Taylor and B Lynch -- Cost-and effectiveness of mitigation measures for reducing emissions to water and air from pastoral farms in Southland, New Zealand / Ronaldo Vibart, I Vogeler, S Dennis, W Kaye-Blake, R Monaghan, V Burggraaf, J Beautrais and A Mackay -- Nitrogen use efficiency in differing dairy wintering systems in Canterbury / John de Ruiter and B J Malcolm -- Impact of climate scenarios on soybean yields in southern Brazil / Frank Eulenstein, M A Lana, S L. Schlindwein, A K Sheudzhen, M Tauscke, E Guevara and S Meira -- Maize for ethanol production: regionalization of responses to climate scenarios, N use efficiency and effectiveness of adaptation strategies / Marcos A Lana, F Eulenstein, S L Schlindwein, M Tauscke, A Behrendt, A K Sheudzhen, J Monk, E Guevara and S Meira -- Developing guidelines for fertiliser spreading on west coast humps and hollows / Abie Horrocks, S Thomas, C Tregurtha, E Meenken and R Horrell -- Whole farm testing: a review of data / Rebecca Withnall and S Bowie -- Effects of holding time and temperature on e. coli and total coliforms in surface water samples / Daniel Mason, K Cooper, J Drysdale, A Dyer, E Meehan, M Stanley and P Lorentz -- Improving the water use efficiency of crop plants by application of mycorrhizal fungi / Marion Tauschke, A Behrendt, J Monk, F Eulenstein and S Monk -- Mycogro AG&#174; - a mycorrhiza product made in New Zealand / Jana Monk -- Serum and faecal zinc concentrations in sheep following low dose oral ZnO treatment / Lisanne F Hageman, P Jeyakumar, S Smith, C W N Anderson -- Can I farm within a phosphorus limit? / Rich McDowell -- Soil water repellency: investigating potential biological drivers and consequences for applied phosphate / Robert Simpson, K Mason, C Robertson and K Mu&#776;ller -- The tiered fertiliser management system for managing soil cadmium in agricultural soils in New Zealand / Greg Sneath -- Developing soil guideline values for the protection of soil biota in New Zealand / Jo Cavanagh -- Spatial distribution of soil cadmium in two long-term dairy farms / Aaron Stafford, C W Anderson and M J Hedley  -- Cadmium in the diet: updating and expanding the exposure model for New Zealand consumers / Andrew Pearson and R Vannoort -- Practical uses of smart technologies /  Jim Wilson -- Variable rate fertiliser application on pastoral hill country - a simple and effective system / Colin Brown -- Precise surveying of soil productivity indicators using on-the-go soil sensors / Colin Hurst, S Lovell, T Lund and A Holmes -- Monitoring &amp; mapping crop development / Dan Bloomer and C Folkers -- Farm system risk analysis: building a farm risk profile to improve farm economic outcomes / Miles Grafton and I J Yule  -- On-farm fertiliser application calibration / Dan Bloomer -- Active light sensing of canopies in crop management: pastures and arable crops / Jessica Roberts, B Scha&#776;bitz and A Werner -- Assessing biomass yield of kale (brassica oleracea var. acephala l.) fields using multi-spectral aerial photography / Jaco Fourie, A Werner and N Dagorn -- Low-cost detection and treatment of fresh cow urine patches / Geoff Bates, B Quin and P Bishop -- Using fertigation as a tool to mitigate nitrogen leaching utilising the increased efficiencies of water and nutrients / Graeme Pile, F Sultanbawa and M Diaz &#8211; Smart irrigation / Andrew Curtis -- Sensors &#8211; what have we got and where are we headed / Ian Yule</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="365"><subfield code="a">Agricultural systems</subfield><subfield code="z">New Zealand</subfield><subfield code="v">Congresses.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="065"><subfield code="a">Agriculture</subfield><subfield code="x">Environmental aspects</subfield><subfield code="z">New Zealand</subfield><subfield code="v">Congresses.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="165"><subfield code="a">Nutrient pollution of water</subfield><subfield code="z">New Zealand</subfield><subfield code="v">Congresses.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="670"><subfield code="a">Currie, L. D.</subfield><subfield code="q">(Lance D.),</subfield><subfield code="e">editor.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="470"><subfield code="a">Burkitt, L. L.,</subfield><subfield code="e">editor.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="2" ind2=" " tag="471"><subfield code="a">Massey University.</subfield><subfield code="b">Fertilizer &amp; Lime Research Centre,</subfield><subfield code="e">issuing body.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="383"><subfield code="a">Occasional report (Massey University. Fertilizer &amp; Lime Research Centre) ;</subfield><subfield code="v">no. 28.</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="4" ind2="0" tag="785"><subfield code="u">http://flrc.massey.ac.nz/workshops/15/Abstract_final_2015.pdf</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1="4" ind2="0" tag="585"><subfield code="u">http://natlib-primo.hosted.exlibrisgroup.com/NLNZ:NLNZ:NLNZ_ALMA21280135700002836</subfield><subfield code="z">Archived copy available at the National Library of New Zealand</subfield><subfield code="x">Open Access</subfield></datafield><datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="194"><subfield code="a">nznb 2017-03</subfield></datafield></record>